Genetics Society of America Records 1921-1982 Mss.575.06.G28p
American Philosophical Society
Genetics Society of America Records
1921-1984
Mss.575.06.G28p
American Philosophical Society
24.5 Linear feet
Founded in 1931, the Genetics Society of America works to facilitate communication among scientists with an interest in research and education in genetics and cognate fields. The GSA Records provide information on the history of the Genetics Society of America from the time of its founding in 1931. Included is correspondence between various officers, members, and outside individuals and organizations, files on standing and ad hoc committees, Records concerning accounts and finances, membership data, files relating to annual meetings, local meetings, and international meetings, and information on special commissions or ad hoc groups of the Society. Among the more noteworthy files are those for the Committee on Genetics, Race, and Intelligence, 1974-1975.
Genetics Society of America.
African American History Note
Of special interest are the records and correspondence documenting the Committee on Genetics, Race, and Intelligence, 1974-1975, which was established to respond to Arthur Jensen and William Shockley.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
It is said that a strong reason for establishing the Genetics Society of America was wide dissatisfaction with the implicit endorsement of eugenics by the older American Genetic Association, to which many geneticists belonged. Many geneticists by 1932 felt that there were both a sufficient number of geneticists and strength of the discipline to warrant a separate society that would unite the animal and plant geneticists in their meetings and programs, if held separately from the times of the botanical and zoological meetings. It was also argued that a separate society would create added support for the periodical Genetics.
Organization of the Genetics Society Records (1 folder) 1929
Seventh International Congress of Genetics Records (6 folders) 1935-1939
Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad Records (6 folders) 1947-1953
Golden Jubilee of Genetics Records (30 folders) 1950
Thirteenth International Congress of Genetics Records (Approximately 200 folders) 1973
Committee on Genetics, Race, Intelligence Records (0.5 linear feet) 1974-1975
Committee on Historical Documents Records (2 linear feet) 1978-1984
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of the Genetics Society of America, 1967-1982.
Scope and Contents note
The Records of the Genetics Society of America provide documentation of the Society's founding and early activities. Files on membership, finances, yearly meetings, and the International Congresses of Genetics provide a sense of the growth of the Society and the discipline and the extension of contacts between American and European
The bulk of the early portion of the Genetics Society collection consists of Records maintained by Secretaries of the Society from 1932 onward. The lack of a continuous home for the Society contributed to the loss of some Records, and to a degree of inconsistency in the organization of those that survived, and the quantity and quality of documentation consequently varies over the years, depending on the interests and habits of the Secretary. In most cases, the bulk of material consists of correspondence to or from the Secretary, with committee reports and Treasurer's Records.
Of special interest are 0.5 linear feet of Records documenting the tumultuous career of the Committee on Genetics, Race, and Intelligence, 1974-1975, which was established in the wake of Arthur Jensen and William Shockley to formulate an official response.
One linear foot of material relates to the Committee on Historical Documents which, during the 1980s, sought to encourage geneticists to preserve the historical record of their field. Among the items in the collection are letters to geneticists inquiring about plans for the disposition of their papers, along with their replies.
The collection is organized chronologically by year, and alphabetically within each year.
Biographical/Historical note
The Genetics Society of America was established in 1931 out of the combination of the Joint Genetics Section of the American Society of Zoologists and the Botanical Society of America, with the aim of facilitating communication among scientists with an interest in research and education in genetics and cognate fields. Periodically, the Society has taken an active stance on issues of public policy relating to genetics, most notably in the debate over the putatively heritable correlation between race and intelligence, the teaching of evolution in American schools, and the issues surrounding recombinant DNA and the genetic modification of organisms.
The official organ of the GSA, Genetics remains one of the most important journals in the field.
American Institute of Biological Sciences.; American Society of Zoologists.; Botanical Society of America; Dunn, L. C., (Leslie Clarence), 1893-1974; Genetics Society of America. Committee on Genetics, Race, and Intelligence.; Glass, Bentley, 1906-2005; Jensen, Arthur Robert; Biology; Biology, genetics, eugenics; Genetics; Genetics--Societies, etc.; Human genetics; International Congress of Genetics; Race; Race, race relations, racism
- Genetics Society of America Records, 1921-1984; 24.5 Linear feet 24.5 lin. feet
  American Association for the Advancement of Science; American Institute of Biological Sciences; American Philosophical Society; Atomic Energy Commission; Botany and plant genetics; Conferences and symposia; Genetics Society of America; Genetics Society of America -- Committee activities; International Congress of Genetics -- Eighth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Eleven Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Ninth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Seventh Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Tenth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Thirteenth Congress; International Congress of Genetics -- Twelfth Congress; National Academy of Sciences; National Institutes of Health; National Research Council; National Science Foundation; Publication; Russian politics and science; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Scientific refugees; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Record of Genetics Sections, 1921-1922 (Box 1)
  - Organization of Genetics Society, 1929; 1 folder (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    * Blakeslee, A.F.
    Castle, W.E.
    Collins, G.
    Demerec, M.
    Emerson, R.A.
    Jones, D.F.
    Landauer, Walter
    Sinnott, E.W.
    Genetics; Genetics Society of America; History of biology, especially genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Records, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Sections, 1930; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Committee on Organization, 1930 (Box 1)
      - Newsletter, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America - Founding, 1930 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Sections Newsletter, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1931; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Founding, 1931 (Box 1)
      - Proposed Constitution, 1931 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1932 (Box 1)
    - American Naturality, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Cole, L. J., 1932 (Box 1)
    - Dunn, L.C., 1932 (Box 1)
    - Genetics, 1932 (Box 1)
      Publication
    - Genetics Society of America, 1932; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Communications, 1932 (Box 1)
      - Atlantic City Meeting, 1932 (Box 1)
        1st Annual
      - Charter Members, 1932 (Box 1)
      - Constitution, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Rickey, F. D., 1932 (Box 1)
    - Stadler, L. J., 1932 (Box 1)
    - Union of American Biological Societies, 1932 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Brink, R.A., 1933 (Box 1)
    - De Vries, Hugo, 1933 (Box 1)
    - Emerson, R.A., 1933 (Box 1)
    - Genetics, 1933 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Cole, L.J., 1934 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1934; 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Election Ballot, 1934 (Box 1)
      - History and Establishment, 1934 (Box 1)
      - Pittsburgh Meeting, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1935 (Box 1)
    - American Society of Zoologists, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Babeoey?, E.B., 1935 (Box 1)
    - Clausen, J., 1935 (Box 1)
    - Cole, L.J., 1935 (Box 1)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1935 (Box 1)
    - East, E, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Emerson, R, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Genetical Societies, Reports of, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1935; 4 folders (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee, 1935 (Box 1)
      - Princeton Meeting, 1935 (Box 1)
      - St. Louis Meeting, 1935 (Box 1)
      - Woods Hole Meeting, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Hayes, H. K., 1935 (Box 1)
    - Heys, Florence M, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Huskins, C Leonard, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Jones, D F, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Landauer, Walter, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Lindstrom, E W, 1935 (Box 1)
    - McClintock, Barbara, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Seventh International Congress of Genetics, 1935 (Box 1)
      Conferences and symposia; Genetics Society of America; International Congress of Genetics -- Seventh Congress
    - Sixth International Botanical Congress, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Shull, George H, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Stadler, L J, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Sturtevant, A H, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Tammes, Tine, 1935 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Whiting, P W, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Akademie Der Wissenschaften, 1936 (Box 1)
      USSR
    - American Society of Naturalists, 1936 (Box 1)
    - American Society of Zoologists, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Banta Publishing Co., 1936 (Box 1)
    - Cole, L J, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Dunn, L C, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Fisher, R A, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Genetical Society of Great Britain, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Genetics, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Gesellschaft Für Vererbungswissenschaft, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1936; 3 folders (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee, 1936 (Box 1)
      - Nominating Committee, 1936 (Box 1)
      - Woods Hole Meeting, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Jones, D F, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Seventh International Congress of Genetics, 1936; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Stern, Curt, 1936 (Box 1)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Wettstein, Fr. von, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Whiting, P W, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Wright, Sewall, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Fisher, R.A., 1936 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Cook, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Dutch Genetic Association, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Genetic Society of Japan, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Genetical Society of Great Britain, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1937; 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Indianopolis Meeting, 1937 (Box 1)
      - Woods Hole Meeting, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Mendelian Society of Lund, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Mohr, Otto L, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Romanian Society of Genetics & Eugenics, 1937 (Box 1)
    - Seventh International Congress of Genetics, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1938 (Box 1)
    - American Society of Zoologists, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Banta Publishing Co., 1938 (Box 1)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Clausen, R E, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Demerec, M, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Dunn, L C, 1938 (Box 1)
    - East, E M, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1938; 6 folders (Box 1)
      - Executive Committee, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Membership Records, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Nominating Committee, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Resolution on Animal Experimentation, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Richmond Meeting, 1938 (Box 1)
      - Woods Hole Meeting, 1938 (Box 1)
    - McClintock, Barbara, 1938 (Box 1)
    - National Research Council of Canada, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Painter, T S, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Seventh International Congress of Genetics, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Stadler, L J, 1938 (Box 1)
    - White, Orland E, 1938 (Box 1)
    - Whiting, P W, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Records, 1939 (Box 2)
    - American Society of Naturalists, 1939 (Box 2)
    - American Society of Zoologists, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Dunn, L C, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Emerson, R A, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Genetics, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Gordon, Myron, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1939; 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Demonstration Material and Exhibits, 1939 (Box 2)
      - Nominating Committee, 1939 (Box 2)
      - Secretary's Report, 1939 (Box 2)
      - Travel Fund Applications, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Jones, D F, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Lewis, R D, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Neal, N P, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Polish Genetical Society, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Seventh International Congress of Genetics, 1939 (Box 2)
    - Snyder, L H, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Beadle, G W, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Botanical Society of America, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Clausen, R E, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Cole, Leon J, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Demerec, M, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Genetics, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1940; 6 folders (Box 2)
      - Executive Committee, 1940 (Box 2)
      - Membership Records, 1940 (Box 2)
      - Minutes of Philadelphia Meeting, 1940 (Box 2)
      - Nominating Committee, 1940 (Box 2)
      - Treasurer's Report, 1940 (Box 2)
      - Woods Hole Meeting, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Muller, Herman J, 1940 (Box 2)
    - National Resources Planning Board, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Stadler, L J, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Union of American Biological Societies, 1940 (Box 2)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Wentworth, Edward N, 1940 (Box 2)
    - Whiting, P W, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Academy of Sciences of the USSR, 1941 (Box 2)
    - American Journal of Botany, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Banta Pub. Co., 1941 (Box 2)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Botanical Society of America, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Dobzhansky, T, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Emerson, Sterling, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Genetics, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America - Secretary's Report, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Lindstrom, E W, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Miller, A L, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Painter, T S, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Patterson, J T, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Randolph, L F, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Rutgers University, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1942 (Box 2)
    - American Association for Advancement of Science, 1942 (Box 2)
    - American Society of Agricultural Sciences, Affiliation with, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Dobzhansky, T, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1942; 4 folders (Box 2)
      - Cancellation of Winter Meeting, 1942 (Box 2)
      - Resolution Concerning Continuation of Research, 1942; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Lindstrom, E W, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Russell, Eliazbeth W, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Sinnott, Edmund W, 1942 (Box 2)
    - Whaley, W Gordon, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1943 (Box 2)
    - American Association for Advancement of Sci., 1943 (Box 2)
    - Beadle, G W, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Blakeslee, Albert F, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Dice, L R, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Dobzhansky, T, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1943; 3 folders (Box 2)
      - Ballot, 1943 (Box 2)
      - Executive Committee, 1943 (Box 2)
      - Newsletter, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Hutt, F B, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Irwin, M R, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Lindstrom, E W, 1943 (Box 2)
    - National Research Council - Division of Biology & Agriculture, 1943 (Box 2)
    - National Roster - Office for Emergency Management, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Reynolds, E B, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Rickey, F D, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Riley, Herbert P, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Sax, Karl, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Schrader, Franz, 1943 (Box 2)
    - Union of American Biological Societies, 1943 (Box 2)
    - U.S. Senate Sub-Committee on War Mobilization, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Abbe, Ernst C, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Adamson, Jane S, 1944 (Box 2)
    - American Association for Advancement of Sci., 1944 (Box 2)
    - American Statistical Association, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Banta Pub. Co., 1944 (Box 2)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Botanical Society of America, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Boyden, Alan, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Cole, Leon J, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Demerec, M, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Domm, L V, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Frolov, T V, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Genetics, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1944; 2 folders (Box 2)
      - Ballot, 1944 (Box 2)
      - Executive Committee, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Kaufmann, B P, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Levine, Philip, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Lindstrom, E W, 1944 (Box 2)
    - MacDowel, Edwin Carleton?, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Paulsen, D F, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Reynolds, E B, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Singleton, W Ralph, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Sonneborn, T M, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Sturtevant, A H, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Taylor, William Randolph, 1944 (Box 2)
    - White, Orland E, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Wines, A, 1944 (Box 2)
    - Wright, Sewall, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Records, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Alexander, Edward P, 1945 (Box 3)
    - American Association for Advancement of Sci., 1945; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Anderson, Edgar, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Banta Pub. Co., 1945 (Box 3)
    - Bennet, Augustus W, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Biological Abstracts, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Blair, Frank W, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Blakeslee, A F, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Braun, Werner, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Buck, John B, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Burnham, Charles B, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Burton, Harold H, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Cambridge University - Department of Genetics, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Connecticut Agricultural Experiment Station, 1945 (Box 3)
      - * Bliss, C I, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Demerec, M, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Dunn, L C, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Fraser, F Clarke, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Fryer, H C, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Genetical Society of Great Britain, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Genetics, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Gowen, John W, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1945; 4 folders (Box 3)
      - Auditing Committee, 1945 (Box 3)
      - Executive Committee, 1945 (Box 3)
      - Membership Records, 1945; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Hull, Fred A, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Hunt, H R, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Italian Society of Genetics and Eugenics, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Kaufmann, B P, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Keeler, Clyde E, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Landauer, Walter, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Langham, D G, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Laughnan, John R, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Lefevre, George Jr., 1945 (Box 3)
    - Lindegren, Carl C, 1945 (Box 3)
    - McClintock, Barbara, 1945; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Mangelsdorf, Paul C, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Mirsky, Alfred E, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Muller, H J, 1945 (Box 3)
    - National Research Council, 1945; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - National Research Council, 1945 (Box 3)
      - Committee on Plant and Animal Stocks, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Netherlands Genetics Society, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Phinney, Bernard, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Purdue University, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Russell, W L, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Sonneborn, T M, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Stern, Curt, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Stone, Wilson S, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Stormont, Clyde, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Sturtevant, A H, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Taylor, W Randolph, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Union of American Biological Societies, 1945 (Box 3)
    - United Nations Food & Agricultural Organization, 1945 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Civil Service Commission, 1945 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Congress - House of Representatives, 1945 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1945 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Public Health Service, 1945 (Box 3)
    - U.S. Senate, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Villie, Claude A, 1945 (Box 3)
    - War Manpower Commission, 1945 (Box 3)
    - Weatherwax, Paul, 1945 (Box 3)
  - Records, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Cooper, Kenneth W, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Dobzhansky, Theodosius, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Domm, L V, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Drexler, R V, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Ellinger, Tage, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Ernst, A, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Fogel, Seymour, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Fryer, H C, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Gaylor, W R, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Genetics, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Goodrich, H H, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1946; 7 folders (Box 4)
      - Ballots, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Executive Committee, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Membership Records, 1946; 2 folders (Box 4)
      - Nominating Committee, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Treasurer's Records, 1946 (Box 4)
      - Treasurer's Report, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Hollaender, Alexander, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Howard, Alva, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Hull, Fred H, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Hutt, F B, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Hutzel, J M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Indian Society of Genetics & Plant Breeding, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Inwin, M Robert, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Kimball, R F, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Langham, D G, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Lesley, J W, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Levine, H P, 1946 (Box 4)
    - McClintock, Barbara, 1946 (Box 4)
    - MacNutt, Wallace, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Mangelsdorf, PAul C, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Margulis Advertising Co., 1946 (Box 4)
    - Martin, Albert, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Missouri Botanical Garden, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Mittler, Sidney, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Monterey Cocker Kennels, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Muller, H J, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Murphy, R P, 1946 (Box 4)
    - National Research Council, 1946 (Box 4)
    - National Roster of Scientific & Specialized Personnel, 1946 (Box 4)
    - New York Academy of Sciences, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Pawar, M S, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Penguin Books, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Pennsylvania Railroad, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Phillips, H M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Pipkin, Sarah Bedichek, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Rick, Charles M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Rhoades, M M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Ryan, Margaret M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Sawin, Paul B, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Sax, Karl, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Science, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Scientific Library, Commonwealth of the Philippines, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Sinnott, Edmund W, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Smith, Ben W, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Snell, George D, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Sonneborn, T M, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Sonnerrblick, B P, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Spoehr, H A, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Stern, Curt, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Stormont, Clyde, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Strong, Leonell C, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Swanson, C P, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Thompson, Ronald B, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Union of American Biological Societies, 1946 (Box 4)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, 1946 (Box 4)
    - W.B. Saunders Co., 1946 (Box 4)
    - Wachtel, Irwin J, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Weir, J A, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Wilson, J Walker, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Zamenhof, Stephen, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Zwilling, E, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Unidentified, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Records, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Society of Naturalists, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Society of Plant Physiologists, 1947 (Box 4)
    - American Society of Professional Biologists, 1947 (Box 4)
    - G. Banta Pub. Co., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Beadle, G W, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Bishop, D W, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Buck, John B, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Carnegie Corp. of New York, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Chesapeake & Ohio Railway Co., 1947 (Box 4)
    - Committee for U.S. Information Abroad, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad, 1947 (Box 4)
      Committee activities; Displaced German scholars; Genetics Society of America -- Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad; Russian politics and science; Scientific refugees
    - Dahlberg, Cunnar, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Domm, L V, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Genetical Society of Great Britain, 1947 (Box 4)
    - Genetics Society of America, 1947; 9 folders (Box 4)
      - Ballots, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Chicago Meeting, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Executive Committee, 1947 (Box 4)
      - Membership Recommendations, 1947; 3 folders (Box 4)
      - Membership Records, 1947 (Box 4)